Now that you know about matrix shapes,
你已经明白矩阵形状
and how they affect the math you can do,
对数学运算的影响
there's something important you need to know about,
现在你需要知道一个重要的知识
the matrix transpose.
即矩阵转置
The transpose of a matrix is a matrix with the same values
矩阵转置是一种运算 得到矩阵的元素的
as the original.
值和原来的一样
But it has the rows and columns switched.
但是行和列的位置被交换了
So the transpose of this square matrix is this matrix.
所以这个方阵的转置是这个矩阵
You can see the values in row 1 of the original matrix,
可以看到原始矩阵第 1 行的值
1, 2, 3, are now the values of column 1 in the transpose.
1 2 3 现在变成转置矩阵第 1 列的值
And the same thing happened for the second and third rows
原始矩阵第 2 行和第 3 行
in the original, becoming the second and third columns
也变成了转置矩阵的第 2 列和
in the transpose.
第 3 列
It works for non-square matrices, too.
非方阵矩阵也是这种情况
The transpose of this is this.
这个矩阵的转置是这个矩阵
Again, you can see how the rows of the original
同样 可以看出原始矩阵的行
become the columns in the transpose.
变成了转置矩阵的列
We really are just swapping the rows and columns.
我们只是交换行和列
But there are two important features of a transpose.
但是转置有两个重要特征
First, if the original matrix wasn't a square,
首先 如果原始矩阵不是方阵
the transpose has a new shape with the original dimensions
那么转置矩阵就会变成新的形状
swapped.
因为维度进行了交换
So the transpose of a 4 by 2 matrix is a 2 by 4 matrix.
所以 4 x 2 矩阵的转置是 2 x 4 矩阵
This can be helpful at times.
有时候这种转置有帮助
For example, if you need to perform a matrix
例如 如果要计算矩阵乘法
multiplication, but the shapes of your matrices
但是矩阵间的形状
are incompatible.
不匹配
The second important thing is that the data in the transpose
第二个重要特征是转置矩阵中的数据
isn't arranged the way it was in the original matrix.
与原始矩阵的数据排列方式不一样
If the original matrix represents rows of data,
如果原始矩阵表示几行数据
the transpose will represent columns.
那么转置矩阵将表示几列数据
And if the original was arranged as columns,
如果原始矩阵按列排列
the transpose will be arranged as rows.
那么转置矩阵将按行排列
Just in case that sounds too abstract,
如果觉得听起来很抽象的话
here's an example of what I mean when I talk about data arranged
我们来看个示例 了解下我说的
as rows or columns.
数据按行或列排列的意思
Imagine we had a matrix that stored the heights, weights,
假设有个矩阵存储的是
and ages of three people.
三个人的身高 体重和年龄
We could choose to store each person's data as a single row
我们可以将每个人的数据存储为一行
or a single column.
或一列
If we choose rows, then each column
如果选择行的话
ends up representing a specific feature for all the people,
那么每列就表示所有三个人的某个特征
like height, weight or age.
例如身高 体重或年龄
However, if we store each person's data as a column,
但是 如果将每个人的数据按列存储
then each row contains all the values for a specific feature.
那么每行就包含特定特征的所有值
But now, imagine we look at the transpose.
但是现在假设我们查看转置矩阵
What used to be rows are now columns, and vice versa.
之前的行变成了列 反之亦然
I've mentioned this multiple times now.
我已经提过好几次
But if you're multiplying two matrices,
如果要对两个矩阵相乘
you're dealing with the rows in the left matrix
其实处理的是左侧矩阵的行
and the columns in the right.
与右侧矩阵的列
This is why this discussion is so important.
这就是为何前面的讨论内容很重要
If you have a math problem working
如果有个数学问题是
with all the features for one person,
处理一个人的所有特征
it's probably different than working with a single feature
那么可能与处理所有人的单个特征
for all the people.
不一样
And most likely, only one of those
很有可能只有一种情况
was actually what you were looking for.
是你要寻找的答案
This is going to come up when you build your neural networks.
当你构建神经网络时 就会遇到这种情况
You'll run into times when some matrix
有时候某些矩阵运算将不可行
operation won't work because the shapes don't line up correctly.
因为形状不对
But then you'll notice it would work
然后你会发现
if you throw in a transpose, like maybe you're
当你进行转置后 就可以了
trying to multiply these 3 by 2 and 4 by 2 matrices.
例如也许你要将这个 3 x 2 和 4 x 2 的矩阵相乘
In the matrix multiplication lessons,
在矩阵乘法课程中
you learned that won't work, because their dimensions
你已经明白这不可行
are incompatible.
因为他们的大小不兼容
Remember, these two inside numbers need to be the same.
注意 内侧的这两个数字需要相同
But here, we have a 2 and a 4.
但是这里是 2 这里是 4
But if you were to take the transpose of the 4 by 2 matrix,
但是如果对 4 x 2 的矩阵进行转置
you'd have a 2 by 4 matrix, and then you
则是 2 x 4 的矩阵
can multiply the 3 by 2 and 2 by 4 matrices.
现在就可以将 3 x 2 和 2 x 4 的矩阵相乘了
Or let's go back and consider another option.
或者回去看看另一个选择
You could take the transpose of the 3 by 2 matrix to get a 2
你可以对 3 x 2 的矩阵转置
by 3 matrix, then swap their orders,
得出 2 x 3 的矩阵 然后交换顺序
and multiply the 4 by 2 and 2 by 3 matrices.
将 4 x 2 和 2 x 3 的矩阵相乘
Mathematically, both of those solutions work.
从数学角度看 二者都可行
But the question is, when you're in that situation,
但问题是 遇到这种情况
should you actually do either of those things?
你应该采取其中的哪一种方法呢？
And the answer is sometimes.
答案是视情况而定
We just need to know when.
我们只需知道何时使用哪个方式即可
Let's go back to trying to multiply these two matrices,
我们再回来试着
a 3 by 2 and a 4 by 2.
将 3 x 2 和 4 x 2 这两个矩阵相乘
We've already shown we can make this multiplication work
我们已经演示了如何使用转置
two different ways using transposes.
通过两种方式使这一乘法可行
But let's see when it is or isn't a good idea.
但是我们来看看这两种方法是否合适
If both of these matrices contain
如果两个矩阵包含的数据
data arranged in rows, then either solution will be fine.
都按行排列 那么两种情况都可行
Using the transpose of the second matrix
对第二个矩阵转置后
gives us rose times columns, and that's
得出行乘以列
exactly what we want for matrix multiplication.
这正是矩阵乘法所需的情形
The answer will be this 3 by 4 matrix.
答案是这个 3 x 4 的矩阵
The second option, where we take the transpose
第二种方法 即对第一个矩阵转置
of the first matrix, and then swap the orders,
然后交换顺序
also gives us rows times columns.
也得出了行乘以列
This time the answer will be this 4 by 3 matrix.
这次将是这个 4 x 3 的矩阵
So that's great.
不错
If both of the original matrices store their data as rows,
如果两个原始矩阵存储的都是行数据
it's safe to use a transpose.
那么就可以使用转置
By the way, you may not have noticed,
顺便提下 你可能没有注意到
but the answers to each of those two multiplications
但实际上这两种乘法的答案
are actually transposes of each other.
相互是转置矩阵
So doing this either way gives you the same numbers,
所以两种情况都得出相同的数字
just with different shapes.
只是形状不一样
That means you can choose either option
意味着你可以选择任一方法
based on the dimensions you want in your result.
具体取决于你希望结果是何种大小
OK, that worked.
这样可行了
But what if the original matrices have
但是如果原始矩阵的数据
their data arranged as columns?
按列排列呢？
In that case, neither option works.
这样的话 两种方法都不可行
Let's see why not.
我们来看看为何
If we used a transpose of the second matrix,
如果我们对第二个矩阵转置
we end up combining the wrong elements with our dot products.
那么就会将错误的元素与点积相加
See, if we look at this row in this column,
如果查看这行和这列
we end up multiplying the 1 and the 0,
结果就是将 1 和 0 相乘
which are each from the first data
每个都来自原始矩阵的
items in the original matrix.
第一组数据项
But then we'd add that to the product of the 2
然后我们会将其与
and the 3, which are each values in the second data items.
2 和 3（第二组数据项）的积相加
So each dot product you take while multiplying these two
所以在对这两个矩阵相乘时
matrices ends up combining values from every data item,
每个点积都会与每个数据项的值相加
rather than combining elements of related items,
而不是我们希望的结果
like we probably intended.
即将相关项的元素相加
This is like what I described earlier, where maybe now we're
这就像我之前描述的情况
looking at the heights of all the people,
也许现在我们查看的是所有人的身高
instead of looking at all the data for just one person.
而不是一个人的所有数据
OK, so taking the transpose of the 4 by 2 matrix
所以对 4 x 2 矩阵转置
won't give us the answer we expect.
并不能得出我们希望的答案
But what about the second option?
那么第二种方法呢？
Here, we use the transpose of the first matrix,
现在对第一个矩阵转置
and then swap them.
然后交换
But it gives us the same problem,
但是出现了相同的问题
data arranged as columns on the left and as rows on the right.
数据在左侧排列成列 在右侧排列成行
How about if the original 3 by 2 matrix
如果原始 3 x 2 矩阵排列成行
had been arranged as rows and the 4 by 2 matrix
4 x 2 矩阵排列成列
had been columns?
结果会怎样？
That actually makes sense, since we
实际上可行
were trying to do this multiplication
因为我们一开始就是想
in the first place.
这么计算乘法的
Unfortunately, neither solution works here either.
遗憾的是 这里两种方法都不行
The first gives us rows times rows.
第一种方法得出行乘以行
And the second gives us columns times columns.
第二种方法得出列乘以列
What about the final possibility,
那么最后一种可能性呢
where the original 3 by 2 matrix had been arranged as columns,
原始 3 x 2 矩阵排列成列
and the 4 by 2 matrix had been rows?
4 x 2 矩阵排列成行
That gives us columns times rows or columns times columns.
结果变成列乘以行或列乘以列
Either way, it's not giving you the answer
无论何种方法
you were looking for.
都无法得出你想要的答案
So it looks like the only time you can safely
所以看来 唯一能够在矩阵乘法中
use a transpose in a matrix multiplication
安全地使用转置的情况就是
is if the data in both of your original matrices
原始的两个矩阵中的数据
is arranged as rows.
都排列成行
Now, I'm not actually trying to say you always
我并不是说你始终需要
need to store data as rows.
将数据存储为行
Sometimes it will make more sense as columns.
有时候存储为列更合适
But just remember, if you run into a situation
但是注意 在某些情况下
where it looks like using a transpose will
如果使用转置
help make some math work--
可以使某些数学运算可行
and you will definitely run into the situation--
你可能会遇到这种情形
then you need to stop and really think about what's
那么你需要停下来好好思考下
in each of your matrices.
每个矩阵的数据情况
Make sure you know which rows and columns need
确保知道哪些行和列
to interact with each other, and then only use transposes
需要进行计算 仅在这些行和列
if they don't mess any of that up. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
不会造成干扰的情况下使用转置